计划奏效了
The plan is working.
我们正在行动
We're doing this.
我们正在获胜
We're winning.
我们经历了艰难的一战
We had a hard fight.
失去了同伴
We lost people,
他们勇敢地献出生命 来确保我们获胜
brave people who gave their lives to make sure we won.
一切尘埃落定时
By the time it was over,
救世军全军覆没
there weren't any Saviors left standing.
我们打败了他们 但情况变复杂了
We beat 'em, but things got complicated.
耶稣收了俘虏 带他们回了家
Jesus took prisoners, brought 'em back home.
我们现在把他们关在门外
We're holding 'em outside our gates for now,
直到我们想好如何处置他们
till we decide what to do.
直到我想好
Until I decide.
我们一点点攻下了哨站
We took the outpost bit by bit.
自以为赢定了
We thought we'd won.
我们聚集在空旷地时 遭到了埋伏
We were gathered up in the open when they ambushed us.
几秒内就结束了
It was over in seconds.
以西结 杰瑞和我
Ezekiel, Jerry, and me,
只有我们活着回来了
we're the only ones who made it back.
这一切
All of it,
比我想象的更恐怖
it's scarier than I thought it'd be,
但我们要行动
but we're doing it.
我们必须如此
We have to.
萨沙是第一个
Sasha was first,
现在有了更多人
and now the's been more.
真真切切有人牺牲
The sacrifices are real.
我们需要为他们而战
We need to make it right for them.
其余的计划依然可行
The rest of the plan's still a go.
我们要继续下一步
We're moving on to the next step.
我现在正前往那里
I'm headed there now.
救世堂仍然被包围着
The Sanctuary's still surrounded.
他们被困住了 没有补给
They're trapped, cut off from their supplies.
随着时间流逝 他们愈发虚弱
Every hour that goes by, we're makin' 'em weaker.
基地周围到处都是警戒的人
The lookouts are all around the compound.
他们敢开门 我们就开火
They open a door, we fire.
但如果他们开门
But if they open a door,
似乎他们有更大的问题
seems like they'd have bigger problems.
两天后我们在救世堂碰头 了结这一切
We meet at Sanctuary in two days to end this,
赢下一切
to win it all.
我们之前并非没有战斗过
It's not like we haven't fought before.
我们一路打拼走到这里
We fought every step of the way to this place,
来到这一刻
to this moment.
这条路带我们来到这里
The path has led us here,
让我们成为这样的人 找到彼此 到达现在
to who we are, to each other, to now.
我们就差一步了
And we're so close.
这可能是我们的最后一场战斗
This can be our last fight.
《行尸走肉》
你留着吧
Yeah, keep it.
耶稣
Jesus.
Jesus…
你给出的是我们的食物
You're giving away our food.
我们的芜菁丰收了 地窖里有很多
We had a bumper crop of turnips in the root cellar.
本来就处理不掉
We couldn't get rid of them.
救世军掠夺我们之后 只留下了它们
Saviors left them behind after they raided us.
地窖的存在是有原因的
That cellar is there for a reason.
也许现在粮食足够 但情况可能有变
We might have plenty now, but that could change.
我们得照顾自己人
We got to look after our own.
保罗 这是场闹剧
Paul, this is a farce.
已经上演够久了
It's gone on long enough.
赶快造个绞刑台吧
I mean, build a gallows already.
你手挺巧 玛格丽特
You're handy, Margaret.
节约子弹 赶快了事吧
Save the bullets and be done with it.
- 格雷戈里… - 怎么
- Gregory… - ?What?
我只是把里面所有人的想法说出来了而已
I'm just saying what everybody inside there is thinking.
进去
Go inside.
马上
Now.
走吧 格雷戈里
Come on, Gregory.
你心里清楚我说的对
You know I'm right.
你不应该把我们置于这种境地
You shouldn't have put us in this position.
你不会真的在考虑按格雷戈里说的做吧
Are you seriously thinking about doing what Gregory said?
每种方案我都会考虑
Every option's on the table.
必须如此
They have to be.
我们到底是在为什么而战 玛姬
What are we fighting for, Maggie?
你知道答案的
You know.
是啊 我以为我知道
Yeah, I thought I did.
所以这些人才会在这里
That's why they're here.
我们必须结束这一切
We have to end this.
- 干掉尼根 - 我们会的
- and Negan. - ?We will.
但当我们成功之后
But when we do,
我们得确保所剩下的
we have to make sure what's left.
比我们失去的更值得
is worth what we lost.
国王不见客
The King is not receiving visitors.
以西结
Ezekiel!
我们答应了要和瑞克及其他人汇合
We promised to meet Rick and the others.
你必须出来
You need to get out here.
我们必须集结剩下的一切战力
We have to gather everyone who can fight.
他都赶我走了
He told me to go, you know.
说不需要我继续做这个了
That I didn't need to do this anymore.
这是我的工作
This is what I do.
我和你一起去
I'll go with you.
- 我要战斗 - 不行
- I'll fight. - ?No.
别跟着我
And don't follow me.
一个人来的
Alone?
是的
I am.
我开枪打了你
I shot you.
擦伤了我
Grazed me.
为什么又来了
Why back after?
和之前原因一样
For the same thing I wanted before.
做交易
A deal.
让我信你
Trust you?
我开枪打了你
Shot you.
你擦伤了我
You grazed me.
假如你真打中了我 我现在一定还气着呢
I woulda still been mad if you'd shot me.
我们杀了你的人
We kill your people.
我们也杀了你的人
We killed some of yours, too.
但我们需要你们 你们也需要我们
But we need you, and you need us.
诡计
Trick.
不是
It's not.
我本可以带着人来 攻占这个地方
I coulda come with my people, taken this place.
你知道我现在人手足够了
You know I have the numbers for that now.
你亲眼见过
You saw it.
然而
Still?
你还是一个人过来了
Alone, you.
需要我们拯救你们
Need us to save you.
不需要了
Not anymore.
救世军完蛋了
The Saviors are finished.
我们攻破了他们的哨站
We took down their outposts.
尼根和他的人被行尸困住了
Negan and his people are trapped by walkers,
上百个行尸
hundreds of them.
不是他们投降…
Until they surrender…
就是我们灭了他们
or we end them.
他们自己选
That's their choice.
如今我也给你们一个选择
Now I'm giving one to you.
听着 我明白 你们「只拿 不费心」
Look, I get it … you take, don't bother.
所以之前你们和尼根做了交易
So you took Negan's deal.
我来是为了给你们一个更好的选择
I'm here to offer a better one.
最终的胜利属于我们
My people will win.
你们还是忘了尼根为好
Your choice is to forget Negan,
再次回到我们这边
switch sides again.
成为新世界的一部分
And be a part of the next world.
亚历山大 山顶寨和神之国
that Alexandria, the Hilltop, and the Kingdom.
共同建立的新世界
will build together.
否则
Or…
我们就灭了你们
we destroy you.
威逼加利诱
Threats and dreams.
利诱加威逼
Dreams and threats.
我的人知道我来这了
Now, my people know I'm here.
你现在的选择
And what they do next.
将决定他们如何行动
depends on what you do right now.
同不同意
Yes or no?
要怎么选
What's it gonna be?
不同意
No.
太聒噪了
Talks too much.
不在其位的人
People who aren't leaders.
总自以为聪明
always think they know better.
总对男领袖指指点点
Always…pointing the finger at the guy,
当然
or, yes, sure,
姑娘你才是领袖
gal who's sitting in the hot seat.
事实上 当领袖并不容易
Truth is, it's not so easy.
我不知道
I don't know.
对我来说 当时不把山顶寨
It was pretty easy for me.
出卖给给尼根挺容易的
not to sell out the Hilltop to Negan.
继续批判我吧 玛格丽特
Go ahead, judge me, Margaret.
我当时做的是对本社区最有利的事
What I did was in the best interest of this community.
怎么个有利法
How?
我的方法不用开一枪
My approach didn't employ bullets,
而是通过外交解决
connect the dots.
你当时很怕
You were scared.
你是想做交易来挽救自己的藏身之处
You tried to cut a deal to save your own hide.
是大家的藏身之处
Not just my hide.
我的动机很纯
My motives were pure.
我知道 玛姬 我们观念不同
I know, Maggie, we, we've had our differences.
但我当过这里的领袖
But I've sat in that chair.
我可以出力
I can help.
我已经进屋了
I'm already in the room.
这是为了让我在思考时 可以盯紧你
So I can keep an eye on you while I think.
盯紧我 得了
Keep an eye on me? Come on.
得有人告诉你
You need someone to tell you.
遵循本能也是可以的
it's okay to follow your gut.
猜怎么的
And guess what?
我就是那个人
I'm that guy.
我们那个会功夫的嬉皮士朋友
Our hippie-dippie kung-fu-fightin' friend.
可能会想让你为此感到内疚
may try and make you feel bad about it,
但归根结底
but at the end of the day,
牧羊人还是你
you're the shepherd.
你不能让狼在羊群中闲逛
And you can't have wolves wandering around amongst the sheep.
就这么简单
It's as simple as that.
瑞克说原地待命
Rick said stay put.
我只是去看看
Just gonna look.
你还在养伤
You're still healing.
好好休息 为下次战斗做准备吧
Get some rest.?Get ready for the next fight.
我很快就回来
I'll be back soon.
你也在养伤
You're still healing.
你中枪了
You were shot.
而我只是被揍了
I was just beat up.
我受过更重的枪伤 开车吧
I've been shot worse than this. Drive.
你刚回来吗
You just get back?
是啊 我刚在找你
Yeah. I was looking for you.
我也在找你
I was looking for you, too.
我想告诉你 你没杀德怀特
I wanted to tell you that you were right.
是对的
when you didn't kill Dwight.
没他我们走不了这么远
We wouldn't have gotten this far without him.
问题是 你说的我都明白
The thing is, I know what you said.
但事成之后 我还是要杀了他
But after this, I'm gonna kill him.
我想自己动手
I want it to be me.
也许可以是你我二人
Maybe it could be you and me both.
也许我们不用等那么久
And maybe we don't got to wait so long.
他们在建什么
What are they building?
不用担心
Don't worry about it.
你自愿做这些事的吗
Did you sign up for this?
当你加入你们团队时
When you joined your group?
我之前 一直孤身一人
I was … I was by myself for a while.
然后我找到了个避风港
Then I found a safe place.
一群幸存者 也是群硬汉
Buncha survivors, buncha tough guys, too.
最终 他们中的一人要当老大
Eventually, one of them took over,
又有人推他下台
and another one took over,
但我并不在意这些
but I wasn't really paying much attention.
因为我不饿肚子就好
'cause, you know, I was gettin' fed.
我手很巧
I'm good with my hands.
他们就派我去卫星站装栅栏
They sent me over to the satellite place to put up a fence.
于是成了这样
Now here we are.
现在我的生死取决于里面管事的女士
Now my life depends on the lady in charge in there.
你可以住口了
You can stop now.
别假装我们中还有谁是无辜者
Don't pretend that any of us are innocent.
他们管你叫什么 耶稣
What do they call you? Jesus?
好 耶稣 我
Well, Jesus, I'm, uh…
我不是天使
I'm no angel.
从没说过我是
Never said I was.
也没有天使这回事
Ain't no such thing.
你出来是为了什么
Why did you need to come out here?
他们进攻救世堂时 我没跟他们去
The second they rolled out to the Sanctuary.
从那一刻起
and I wasn't with them…
就好像
…it's like.
有个
this…
警铃在我脑中响起
siren's been going off in my head.
我关不掉
I can't turn it off.
是我促成了这事
I helped get this started.
已经过了一天半
It's been a day and a half.
我能感受到每一秒的流逝
And I have felt every second.
所以我必须去看看
So I just need to see it.
关掉我脑中的警铃
Turn that alarm off in my head.
然后转身回家
and turn around and go back home.
好
Okay.
停车
Stop the car.
听
Listen.
我不觉得那声音能传到救世堂
I don't think that sound could reach the Sanctuary.
我也不觉得
I don't, either.
但我们没法确定
But we don't know.
那是我爸爸
It was my dad.
擦过你头顶的只是鸣枪警告
There … There were warning shots above your head.
他没瞄你
He wasn't shooting at you.
我是卡尔
I'm Carl.
西迪克
Siddiq.
食物和水
Food and water.
为什么帮我
Why?
我猜你
I guess you …
你说你妈妈曾说过一些话
you were talking about something your mom said…
要帮助别人
about helping people.
我妈妈告诉我 必须做正确的事
有时很难知道什么才是正确的事
It's hard to know what that is sometimes,
但有时并不难
but sometimes it's not.
谢谢
Thanks.
很庆幸我找到了你
Glad I found you.
你在找我吗
You were looking for me?
是的 我找到了沙丁鱼罐头
Yeah, I … I scavenged the sardines,
还有其他东西
other stuff.
我和我爸爸属于一个社区
Me and my dad, we're in a community.
我要问你几个问题
I'm gonna ask you a few questions.
- 你必须诚实回答 好吗 - 好的
- I need you to answer honestly, okay? - Okay.
你杀过多少行尸
How many walkers have you killed?
- 我知道很难记清 - 237只
- I know it's hard to keep track … - 237.
真的吗
Really?
误差一两只吧
Give or take a couple.
你杀过多少人
How many people have you killed?
一个
One.
为什么
Why?
行尸想杀他 但
The dead tried to kill him, but…
没杀成
they didn't.
你在设置行尸陷阱
You're making walker traps.
你就是靠这招杀死那么多行尸的吗
Is that how you killed so many?
这只是其中一部分
It's … It's only part of it.
我妈妈认为 或是说希望 杀死它们能
My mom thought or hoped that killing them would…
释放它们的灵魂
free their souls.
你懂吗
You know?
也许 也许她是对的
Maybe … Maybe she was right.
那样做不会让一切更难吗
Doing that, doesn't that just make things harder for you.
因为你还在努力求生
while you're trying to survive?
我不知道
I … I don't know. I…
但你得
But you gotta …
你得听父母的话 不是吗
you gotta honor your parents, right?
如果我听我爸的话
If I was honoring my dad,
我们现在就不会对话了
we wouldn't be talking right now.
我也绝不会带你回我们社区
And definitely wouldn't bring you back to my community.
我说了 别跟着我
I told you not to follow me!
你知道孩子在树林里乱跑
Do you know what happens to kids.
会有什么结果吗
when they go wandering around in the woods?
再也不会有人看见他们
They never get seen again,
就算看见了 他们也变成怪物了
and if they do, they're monsters.
- 这是你想要的吗 - 我不怕
- Is that what you want? - I'm not scared.
那你愚蠢至极
Then you're stupid.
你需要战士 所以我在战斗
You need fighters, so I'm fighting.
刚才
Just now,
你是想独自回到救世军那里吗
were you gonna go back to the Saviors' place by yourself?
让我跟你一起去
Let me go with you.
我必须找到杀了我哥哥的人
I have to get the guys who killed my brother.
你不能就拿着根棍子到处走
Can't just walk around with that stick.
你知道怎么用吗
You know how to use it?
我看过你训练其他人
I watched you train people.
跟紧点
Stay close.
不准打开保险 除非我发话
The safety stays on until I say otherwise.
还是不担心吗
Still not worried?
玛姬说带他们进去
Maggie says to bring them in.
让他们进去
Get them in.
走吧
Come on.
一次两个人
Two at a time.
从现在起 我们把囚犯关在这里
Starting now, we'll keep the prisoners here.
我们给他们食物
We'll feed them.
不虐待他们
We won't mistreat them.
但我们不容许丝毫的不配合
But we won't stand for anything less than total cooperation.
玛格丽特 恕我直言
Margaret, all … all due respect,
我就直话直说了
I'm just straight-shooting here.
你不能让我们不信任的人
You can't let people we don't trust.
在围墙里东奔西跑
run around inside our walls.
你说得对 格雷戈里
You're right, Gregory.
事实上 我一直在想
In fact, I couldn't stop thinking about.
你昨晚跟我说的话
what you told me yesterday.
我从小在农场长大
You see, I grew up on a farm.
我对狼和羊很熟悉
I know all about sheep and wolves.
你们干什么
What are you doing?
你们做什么
- 来吧 格雷戈里 - 放开我
- Come on, Gregory. - Let go of me.
不要
No.
凯尔 你真要这样吗 爱德华多
Kal, are you serious? Eduardo?
等等 这不能
Wait! This … This can't …
- 等等 - 冷静
- Wait. - ?Calm down.
不要 别叫我冷静
No, don't tell me to calm down.
我不进去
I am not gonna go in there.
你不能这样 玛姬
You can't! Maggie!
听着 别 等等 住手
Look, just … No, wait, stop!
- 等一下 - 冷静
- Just for a minute! - Calm down!
不要 求你了 不要 老天
No, please, no! No! God!
天啊 我什么都没做
Oh, God. I didn't do anything.
我什么都没做
I didn't do anything. I …
亲爱的
Oh, honey…
你会害死这些人的
you're gonna get these people killed.
你已经害死几个人了 没错吧
Well, you already got some people killed, didn't you?
谢谢
Thank you.
不要让我后悔这么做
Don't make me regret it.
不然你会后悔的
Or you will.
好吧
Okay.
为了你妈妈
For your mom.
你快走 你不用这样做
Just go!?You don't have to do this!
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
你可以走的
You could've left.
卡尔
Carl.
现在我对你负责了
I'm responsible for you now.
就是这样
That's how it works.
我不想带来任何麻烦
I don't want to make any trouble.
你爸爸不想和我有任何关系
Your dad didn't want anything to do with me.
他是不想 但是
He didn't, but…
有时子女要找到自己的方式
sometimes kids have to find their own way.
来警醒父母
to show their parents the way.
外面有辆房车 已经烧毁了
There was an RV out front that was all burned to hell.
应该是那个混蛋瑞克的车
Think it was that asshole Rick's ride.
好吧 所以呢
Okay. So?
尼根烧死了那混球
Negan torched the piece of shit.
- 又怎样 - 或者
- So what? - ?Or …
或者是他们干的
Or they did.
你想想
Think about it.
大门被撞开了
That gate was ripped open.
房车炸弹就像行尸的吃饭铃一样
And an RV bomb is one hell of a dinner bell for the dead.
没错 但是这并不意味着那有过交火
Yeah, but that doesn't mean there was a fight.
得了吧 泽 肯定有
Come on, Zee, there had to be.
肯定有人在那交过火
That was definitely a battle back there.
我敢打赌
And I'm betting.
他们就是为了包围大房子
it was all about surrounding the big house.
可能还有些尸道上来的行尸
Probably with some rots from the Herdway.
好吧 不管发生了什么 不管现在怎样
Yeah, well, whatever happened, whatever is happening,
混蛋瑞克 或者其他什么人
Rick the prick, or whoever,
都对这里的「胖女人」一无所知
they don't know shit about "The Fat Lady" here.
局势可以被迅速扭转
What's been done can be undone real quick.
我们让「胖女人」唱起来 救他们的命
We get her singing, we save their asses.
我想尼根会给我们些好处的
And I think Negan's gonna give us a leg up.
不用再他妈拾荒了
No more of this scavenging bullshit.
那赶紧搞好啊
Well, then, get it done, then.
快点
Come on.
好了
That about does it.
检查周边
Check the perimeter!
确保没其他人
Make sure no one else is here.
好
Yeah.
你看起来不太好 姑娘
You don't look so good, girl.
有人揍过你吗
Somebody tune you up?
里奥
Leo!
快去救世堂
Get your ass to the Sanctuary!
我来对付她们
Leave 'em to me!
罗西塔 拦住他
Rosita, stop him!
放下枪
Drop it.
小姑娘 你不会用那玩意的…
Baby girl, you're not gonna use that thing…
罗西塔
Rosita!
天啊 就差一点
Jesus, that was too close.
是啊
Yeah.
的确
It was.
一卡车音箱
Truck full of speakers, huh?
那人是救世军
That was a Savior.
没错
Yeah, it was.
你们攻击救世堂时
They were scavenging.
他们在外搜寻补给
when you guys attacked the Sanctuary.
他们看到行尸包围了那里
They saw all the walkers around it.
这是个武器库
It's a cache.
他们打算引走行尸
They were gonna try and drive the walkers away.
所以他们才来这里
That's why they were out here.
你们为什么来这里
Why are you guys out here?
我要去看看救世堂
I need to see the Sanctuary.
我们都是
We both do.
你们为什么来这里
Why are you out here?
我们有很多工作要做
We got a lot more work to do.
我们所有人
All of us.
- 他依然不见客 - 杰瑞
- He's still not seeing anyone. - Jerry…
和亨利站一起
stand next to Henry.
捂住耳朵
Cover your ears.
喂
Yo!
门没锁
The door's not locked.
我知道你想要我做什么
I know what you want from me…
我知道我该做什么
what I should be doing.
但我做不到
But I can't.
外面的人需要你
People out there need you.
我有什么资格替他们做选择
Who the hell was I to choose for them?
你是他们的国王
You're their king.
那是因为我自称是国王
'Cause I said I was a king.
我扮演了个角色
I played a part.
很早以前
And early on,
我看到了代价是这些人的性命
I was shown that the stakes were these people's lives.
而我依然在演
And I still played the part.
我知道的
I knew.
而我依然在笑
And yet I smiled.
我演不下去了
I can't do it no more.
我成不了他们需要的人
I can't be what they need.
所以 求你…
So, please just…
别来找我了
leave me alone.
你为什么一直来看我
Why did you keep coming to visit me?
那是我的职责
It was my duty.
确保你安全
To make sure you were okay.
我很安全
I was okay.
你到底为什么来
Why did you really?
你只是…
You just…
让我觉得自己是真实的
…made me feel real.
不是虚构的
Not a fiction.
真实
Real.
你是真实的
You are real.
对我来说
To me.
对神之国来说
To the Kingdom.
那些人需要国王领导他们
Those people need their king to lead them.
你
You.
你可以领导他们
You could lead them.
必须是你
But it has to be you.
你激励他们建立了这地方
You inspired them to build this place…
让他们有所信仰
to believe in something.
你必须帮他们哀悼
You have to help them grieve,
从痛苦中走出 终结这一切
to move on, to end this.
这是你欠他们的
You owe them that.
亨利需要你
Henry needs you.
那些人需要以西结国王
Those people need King Ezekiel.
如果你不能成为国王
And if you can't be the king,
那就做你最擅长的事 演好这个角色
then do what you do best and play the part.
我必须每天都演
I have to act every day.
以前令我很苦恼
It used to bother me.
但我就是这样的人
But this is who I am,
而且我依然活着
and I am still standing.
我必须假装一切正常 直到真的正常
I just have to act like everything is normal until it is.
这是他们所需要的
It's what they need,
也是你必须给他们的
and it's what you have to give them.
我做不到
I can't.
你已经搞砸一次了
You already screwed up once.
我不会让你害死我们的
I'm not gonna let you get us all killed.
你觉得他们会杀我们吗
You think they're gonna kill us?
撑住 这地方迟早会是我们的
Just keep it together. This place is gonna be ours.
我总是忘记他不在了
I keep… forgetting he's gone.
我心里有个念想
I have this…weight.
有时候 我觉得我会见到他
There's moments when I … I think I'll see him,
我可以…
that I'll, uh…
和他谈谈我的感受
be able to talk about how I'm feeling with him.
然后我反应过来
And my mind catches up,
我想起来痛苦之处
and I remember that the pain.
就是知道那永远不会发生
is about knowing?that it will never happen.
我知道那种感觉
I know that feeling.
- 以后会好受些吗 - 不会
- Does it get easier??- No.
但这会鞭策你做一些事
But it helps to do something about it.
他怎么样
How is he?
格雷戈里没事
Gregory's fine.
他正在拍救世军的马屁
He's trying to suck up to the Saviors now.
我只想说
I just wanted to say,
我觉得你做了正确的事
I think you did the right thing.
- 我想感谢你 - 别谢我
- And I wanted to thank you. - Don't.
围栏里的救世军或许能当谈判筹码
The Saviors in that pen might be bargaining chips.
或许我们以后得拿他们换我们的人
Maybe we'll have to trade them for some of our own people.
他们活着是因为我们也许用得上他们
They're alive 'cause we might need them.
耶稣 如果用不上
Jesus, if we don't…
我们不能留他们活口
we can't let them live.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
去确保我们赢
To make sure we win.
带我一起去
Let me come with you.
你说得对
You're right.
我们必须赢
We need to win.
拿上你的东西
Grab your stuff.
和一些食物
And some food.
我们也许会走一段时间
We might be gone for a while.
给 你想看的
Here you go. You wanted to see it.
你要我们做什么
So what do you need us for?
终结这一切 现在就终结
To end this thing … right now.